

SAAD AFZAL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

Email

mu.saadafzal@gmail.com

Phone

+49 15753600829

Address

Vetterstrasse 66/526 09126 Chemnitz, Germany

SKILLS

- PHP
- Laravel
- Codelgniter
- Yii
- React JS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Postgres SQL
- JSON
- Docker
- Git

LANGUAGES

Urdu - Native

English - Advanced

German - Beginner

ABOUT ME

Software developer with 3 years of experience in developing web applications using industry-leading technologies, with a passion for learning new technologies, loves to automate stuff and bring new ideas to the table, looking for a role as a working student developer which provides challenge and opportunity for professional and personal growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Working Student

August 2021 - present

InterOffice GmbH - Dresden, Saxony

Developed and debugged several features in Configurators application as provided by the end-users.

Improved user interface and functionality for the existing application to optimize end-user experience.

Software Engineer

April 2020 - March 2021

F3 Technologies - Islamabad, Pakistan

Developed Educational Institute Management System, to automate daily academic tasks in institutes.

Documented Product Journey, milestones, deliverables and facilitated communication amongst stakeholders and teams.

Collaborated in onboarding and deployment of the application to 5 different instututes.

Developed core application features and worked on WebRTC to provide a customized virtual class environment to end-users.

Junior Software Developer

February 2019 - April 2020

Nexus Technologies - Islamabad, Pakistan

Developed Web applications (Ignite - Pakistan) that facilitate the Government to onboard and manage startups in the country.

Developed Scholarship Management System for the Company as an in-house product of the company as a Full Stack developer using Laravel, MySQL, Bootstrap, JavaScript.

TV - Saad Afzal 1/2

EDUCATION

Master's Degree

Technical University of Chemnitz, Web Engineering - Chemnitz, Saxony

CERTIFICATIONS

Responsive Web Design (FreeCodeCamp), JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (FreeCodeCamp)

CV - Saad Afzal 2/2

2023